Saif Ul Malook

saifulmalook1@hotmail.com

www.saifulmalook.co.uk 0794-3434-828

Personal Profile

An energetic and imaginative Junior Developer with two years practical experience on small self-Projects and with a small web development business. Has the ability to identify and understand industry issues and trends, particularly in regard to accessibility, usability and emerging technologies. In addition, is an ambitious person who works hard to get noticed, has the drive and displays the energy and aptitude needed to really make a difference to any given project. Currently seeking an exciting opportunity within a Junior Developer in Web, Cloud or Software developments.

Education

Loxford School of Science and Technology

September 2007- July 2010

BTEC Level 3 in Business Studies – Pass

Loxford School of Science and Technology

September 2005 - July 2007

- GCSE Design and Technology: Systems & Control Technology A
- GCSE Maths- B
- GCSE English B
- GCSE Double Science B, B
- GCSE Business Studies B
- GCSE Spanish B
- GCSE English Literature C
- Level 2 NVQ Certificate in Team Leading
- GNVQ in ICT Pass

Work Experience

Websolutions (London) Limited

June 2016 - Present

www.websolutions.services

Junior Web Developer (Freelancing)

- Creating landing pages
- Front End technologies, Html Css3 and JavaScript and Website Templates
- WordPress
- Hosting and deployment
- GitHub, FTP, Bootstrap PHPStorm
- Some Graphics Designing
- Bug Fixing

Southern Housing Group

July 2017

Audit / data entry with Employment team:

- Compiling all data to update new Love London Working programme
- Completing the updating and computer analysis of various strands of the programme
- Assisting employment skills officers with their data information and auditing same
- Assisting administrator with additional information uploaded onto new systems
- Working with senior employment skills officer to improve systems

Ocado

Jan 2016 - July 2016

CSTM(Customer service team member)Delivery Driver:

- Delivering groceries to our customers in timed delivery slots
- Providing outstanding customer service
- Maintaining timely communication by phone with our customers to keep them informed of issues or changes to their proposed delivery.

Eurocar Parts

Oct 2014 - Feb 2015

Delivery Driver

Duties included:

- Preparing the delivery
- Getting the itinerary ready
- Preparing a manifest
- Driving to garages and delivering items

Silver Star Rentals Administration/Finance

May 2012 - Oct 2014

Duties included:

- Monthly reconciliation of accounts
- Chasing customers
- Chasing and collecting rent
- Preparing payments/invoices/sales receipts
- Keeping in contact with customers
- Keeping up with Data Protection policies, insurance companies and local authorities
- Making sure the cars are well maintained and up to record

Farm Foods Ltd

May 2011 - May 2012

Assistant branch Manager

Duties included:

- Hiring and training new employees
- Monitoring inventory and ensuring customer satisfaction
- Managing levels of stock through corrective methods of ordering
- Key areas of responsibility included store operations, labour management, financial administration, health and safety and supply management
- Liaising with head office and relevant departments
- Daily, weekly and monthly diligence
- Ensuring health and safety at all times
- Dealing with customer complaints

Farm Foods Ltd Retail Assistant

Nov 2010 - May 2011

Ketan Assistan

Duties included:

- Helping customers to find the goods they want
- Advising on stock amounts
- Giving information on products and prices
- Answering customer enquiries or passing them on to another department
- Giving information and helping to solve problems
- Selling products or taking orders
- Taking payment for goods or services
- Giving refunds

Achievements/Volunteering

- A Youth Board Member for Talent match London (Canning Town, East London) who help 16-24 into the world of work. Been volunteering for 1 year. Mentoring and planning programmes as well as events
- Won the Mayors Fund for London Competition to help 16-24 in the world of work
- Received a ceremonial commendation for systems and control at secondary school was presented in front of the whole school
- As a hobby and trial to test my own knowledge I have coded a HTML5 website with related information to my portfolio. www.saifulmalook.xyz

Key Skills

- Organised approach with excellent time management skills and Vast and diverse skills of team management
- Excellent English and Numerical Skills
- Ability to work well as part of a team.
- Accuracy and attention to detail.
- Experience with cPanel, WHM and WHMCS
- Solving client's technical issues
- Responsive websites www.namaastekitchen.co.uk salaam-namaste.co.uk
- XAMPP and FTP on daily use
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap and WordPress
- Experience with Photoshop
- Applying security with best practice
- Trello/Slack for Task Management/Communication
- Backup, Restore and Migration
- GitHub
- Basic Knowledge NodeJS, MVC, PHP
- Able to work on own initiative and solve Technical problems
- Logical Approach
- Proficient with Microsoft Office software's
- Some knowledge of how to create a database and relationships using Microsoft Access software
- Improving knowledge with always staying up to date and asking questions
- The ability to learn quickly, interpret and follow technical plans with a excellent use of google search engine
- An understanding of confidentiality and data protection issues

Interests

I have always been interested in technology from which my passion for programming languages stems. I like developing basic web applications to better my knowledge in the field as well as researching on the web, watching tutorial videos of programming and learning HTML5 in more depth. This hobby translates into my effort and passion I put into any task, gives me the motivation to succeed.

References are available upon request Also Portfolio Pieces available upon Request